<referencegroup anchor="BCP.185" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/bcp185">
  <reference anchor="RFC.7115" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc7115">
    <front>
      <title>Origin Validation Operation Based on the Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI)</title>
      <author fullname="R. Bush" initials="R." surname="Bush">
        <organization/>
      </author>
      <author>
        <organization>RFC Series</organization>
      </author>
      <date year="2014" month="January"/>
      <workgroup>sidr</workgroup>
      <abstract>
        <t>Deployment of BGP origin validation that is based on the Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI) has many operational considerations. This document attempts to collect and present those that are most critical. It is expected to evolve as RPKI-based origin validation continues to be deployed and the dynamics are better understood.</t>
      </abstract>
    </front>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC7115"/>
    <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="185"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="7115"/>
    <seriesInfo name="IETF"/>
  </reference>
  <reference anchor="RFC.9319" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc9319">
    <front>
      <title>The Use of maxLength in the Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI)</title>
      <author fullname="Y. Gilad" initials="Y." surname="Gilad">
        <organization/>
      </author>
      <author fullname="S. Goldberg" initials="S." surname="Goldberg">
        <organization/>
      </author>
      <author fullname="K. Sriram" initials="K." surname="Sriram">
        <organization/>
      </author>
      <author fullname="J. Snijders" initials="J." surname="Snijders">
        <organization/>
      </author>
      <author fullname="B. Maddison" initials="B." surname="Maddison">
        <organization/>
      </author>
      <author>
        <organization>RFC Series</organization>
      </author>
      <date year="2022" month="October"/>
      <workgroup>sidrops</workgroup>
      <abstract>
        <t>This document recommends ways to reduce the forged-origin hijack attack surface by prudently limiting the set of IP prefixes that are included in a Route Origin Authorization (ROA). One recommendation is to avoid using the maxLength attribute in ROAs except in some specific cases. The recommendations complement and extend those in RFC 7115. This document also discusses the creation of ROAs for facilitating the use of Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) mitigation services. Considerations related to ROAs and RPKI-based Route Origin Validation (RPKI-ROV) in the context of destination-based Remotely Triggered Discard Route (RTDR) (elsewhere referred to as "Remotely Triggered Black Hole") filtering are also highlighted.</t>
      </abstract>
    </front>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC9319"/>
    <seriesInfo name="BCP" value="185"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="9319"/>
    <seriesInfo name="IETF"/>
  </reference>
</referencegroup>